The Cuneen Hackett Family Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
The Cuneen Hackett Family Papers
1850 - 1957
NPkMC-222-115
7.5 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Cunneen-Hackett Family
The Cunneen-Hackett Papers consists of materials from the estate of Charlotte Cunneen-Hackett. Various belongings including family Bibles, books concerning religious and nature themes, personal journals, diaries and photo albums are included in the collection. There is also another section dedicated to correspondence of New York State Senator Hatfield and information regarding Senate Bills he was influential in forming.
Collection Overview
The Cunneen Hackett Papers consists of family Bibles, religious, nature and other misc. books, personal journals, photo albums and artifacts. Senator Hatfield’s correspondence with local citizens and businesses as well as his Senate bills and information concerning the bills is included.
Acquisitions Information
Former attorney for the Cunneen-Hackett estate John Gartland presented the collection to Marist College.
Historical Note
The Cunneen-Hackett’s were an influential family from the Poughkeepsie area that took an active role in local politics and law. John Mulford Hackett, a successful lawyer and assemblyman for Dutchess County, and his wife Charlotte Cunneen, also a lawyer, were married in 1919 and established themselves in the Hudson Valley. Although they never had children, they both became involved in many social and civic activities centering on the education, religion and encouragement of children. After John’s death in 1954, Charlotte continued reaching out to the community and became an important supporter for the local boys and girls scout troops. Charlotte passed away in 1971 but a charitable trust fund left in her will allows her generous memory to live on. Former Trustee John J. Gartland Jr. channeled the income from her fund to various causes in the Hudson Valley, such as the donation of her home to the Boy Scouts, the restoration of the Vassar Home and Institute into the Cunneen-Hackett Cultural Arts Center as well as to projects at Marist College.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into three series: 1) Books of the Cunned-Hackett's has six subseries, 2) Senator Hatfield has three subseries, and 3) Artifacts
Series are arranged by subject or chronologically
- 1. Books of the Cunneen-Hackett’s, 1836 - 1979; 1; 4.5 Linear Feet Boxes: 1 - 3 Folders: 1 - 37
  Series contains books from the Cunneen-Hackett Papers which includes 4 Bibles, 20 books concerning religion, nature and other miscellaneous subjects, and 13 personal journals and photograph albums.
  Books in Subject order and MLA format. Personal journals and albums are chronological.
  - Subseries 1.1: Bibles, 1850 - 1863; 1.1; Box: 1 Folders: 1 - 4
    - The Holy Bible (1850) (Folder 1, Box 1)
    - Holy Bible (1858) (Folder 2, Box 1)
    - The Holy Bible (1863) (Folder 3, Box 1)
    - The Holy Bible (undated) (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - Subseries 1.2: Religious Books, 1898 - 1947; 1.2; Box: 2 Folders: 5 - 12
    - Common Prayer and the Hymnal. NY: Oxford University Press, 1898. (Paperback) (Folder 5, Box 2)
    - Dawson, Coningsby. The Seventh Christmas. NY: Henry Holt and Company, 1917. (Hardcover) (Folder 6, Box 2)
    - Good News for Modern Man, the New Testament in Today’s English. NY: American Bible Society 1966 (paperback) (Folder 7, Box 2)
    - Hall, Bennie Caroline. Spiritual Diary. NY: Jordan House, 1940, (Hardcover) (Folder 8, Box 2)
    - New Testament and Psalms. NY: American Bible Society: 1848. (Hardcover) (Folder 9, Box 2)
    - Rice, Helen Steiner. “Just for You” a Special Collection of (Folder 10, Box 2)
    - Rodriguez, H. Manuel. Cancionero Juvenil (Religious music). Madrid, 1947. (Hardcover) (Folder 11, Box 2)
    - The Book of Common Prayer. NY: Oxford University Press, 1935. (Hardcover) (Folder 12, Box 2)
  - Subseries 1.3: Nature Books, 1904 - 1931; 1.3; Box: 2 Folders: 13 - 18
    - Chapman Frank M., What Bird is That? NY: D. Appleton and Company, 1920. (Hardcover) (Folder 13, Box 2)
    - Mathews, Schuyler F. Field Book of Wild Birds and Their Music. NY: Knickerbocker Press, 1904. (Hardcover) (Folder 14, Box 2)
    - Poucher, J. Wilson. Stories of the Wild Flowers. NY: 1931. (Hardcover) (Folder 15, Box 2)
    - Reed, Chester A. Bird Guide. NY: Doubleday, Page & Co., 1920. (Hardcover) (Folder 16, Box 2)
    - Reed, Chester A. Flower Guide. NY: Doubleday, Page & Co., 1917. (Hardcover) (Folder 17, Box 2)
    - Rogers, Julia Ellen. Tree Guide. NY: Doubleday, Page & Co., 1922. (Hardcover) (Folder 18, Box 2)
  - Subseries 1.4: Misc. Books, 1920 - 1973; 1.4; Boxe: 2 Folders: 19 - 24
    - Bennett, C.E. Advance and Retreat to Saratoga in the American Revolution. NY: Robson, Adee, Schenectady, 1927. (Paperback) (Folder 19, Box 2)
    - In Washington. Daughters of the American Revolution Washington DC: 1965. (Paperback) (Folder 20, Box 2)
    - Ruckeyser, Muriel. The Colors of the Day a Celebration of the Vassar Centennial. NY: May 10, 1961. (Paperback) (Folder 21, Box 2)
    - Seward’s, W.H. Travels Around the World. NY: D. Appleton and Company, 1873. (Hardcover) (Folder 22, Box 2)
    - The Giwell Book. Boy Scouts Association. London: C.J. Cousland & Sons Ltd., 1965. (Hardcover) (Folder 23, Box 2)
    - Van Dyke, Henry. The Story of the Other Wise Man and the Mansion. NY: Harper & Brothers, 1920. (Hardcover) (Folder 24, Box 2)
  - Subseries 1.5: Personal Journals and Diaries, 1836 - 1961; 1.5; Box: 3 Folders: 25 - 30
    - Law diary of an apprentice lawyer “interning” at a law office 1836 (Folder 25, Box 3)
    - Family records of births and marriages 1846 (Folder 26, Box 3)
    - Private diary of Charlotte Cunneen, November12, 1907 (Folder 27, Box 3)
    - Marriage diary of John Mulford Hackett and Charlotte -Elizabeth Cunneen. Includes marriage certificate and John Hackett Sr.’s citizenship Papers February 12, 1957 (Folder 28, Box 3)
    - Travel Journal of Mrs. John Mulford Hackett May 10, 1961 (Folder 29, Box 3)
    - Personal prayer book (Folder 30, Box 3)
  - Subseries 1.6: Photography and albums, 1900 - 1979; 1.6; Box: 3 Folders: 31 - 37
    - Photo album of Hudson Valley and friends/family September, 1903 (Folder 31, Box 3)
    - Photo album, 1900’s-10. (Folder 32, Box 3)
    - John Hackett’s photo album from 1912 (Folder 33, Box 3)
    - Photo album of family and Hudson 1950’s-60’s (Folder 34, Box 3)
    - Photo album of home and family/friends 1950’s-60’s (Folder 35, Box 3)
    - Travel Journal of Mrs. John Mulford Hackett May 10, 1961 (Folder 36, Box 3)
    - Report of Charlotte Cunneen Hackett Charitable Trust for the Years 1972-79 (Folder 37, Box 3)
    - Picture of John Hackett’s Home (presently Boy Scout -Headquarters) (Folder 38, Box 3)
- 2. Senator Hatfield, 1953 - 1958; 2; 2.5 Linear Feet Boxes: 4 - 5 Folders: 38 - 72
  Series contains personal letters of the senator to various citizens and businesses concerning the passage of 12 bills and misc. correspondence. Other Information, research and reports about the bills are also included.
  Subject and chronological order
  - Subseries 2.1: Senator Hatfield’s correspondence, 1954 - 1957; 2.1; Box: 4 Folders: 38 - 53
    - February/ March 1954, Concerning Compulsory Automobile Liability Insurance (Folder 38, Box 4)
    - January-March 1955, Concerning Rent Control (Folder 39, Box 4)
    - December 1955- February 1956 Misc. Correspondence (Folder 40, Box 4)
    - February 1956, Health Services in Schools (Folder 41, Box 4)
    - January 1956-March 1956, Concerning Special License -Plates for Amateur Radio Stations (Folder 42, Box 4)
    - January-March 1956- Concerning public education (Folder 43, Box 4)
    - January 1956-March 1956- Personal correspondence and invitations (Folder 44, Box 4)
    - January 1956- April 1956, Concerning Unemployment and Workman’s Compensation (Folder 45, Box 4)
    - February/March 1956- Concerning Engineer licensing in NY State (Milmoe Bill) (Folder 46, Box 4)
    - March 1956, Concerning Liquor License Fees (Folder 47, Box 4)
    - March 1956 Concerning Licensing of psychologists (Folder 48, Box 4)
    - March 1956 Misc. Correspondence (Folder 49, Box 4)
    - April 1956-Feb 1957 Misc. Correspondence (Folder 50, Box 4)
    - January 1957-“To amend the education law in relation to -advertising Physicians” (Folder 51, Box 4)
    - February 1957- Concerning State Insurance Fund (Folder 52, Box 4)
    - February/March 1957- Concerning “Time off to Vote” Bill (Folder 53, Box 4)
  - Subseries 2.2: Senate Acts, 1953 - 1958; 2.2; Box: 4 Folders: 54 - 56
    - Feb 1953-March 1957 Various Senate Bills (Folder 54, Box 4)
    - Jan-Feb 1957 Book of Senate Bills of Senator Hatfield (Folder 55, Box 4)
    - Jan-Feb 1958 Book of Senate Bills of Senator Hatfield (Folder 56, Box 4)
  - Subseries 2.3: Information, Research, Reports, 2.3; Boxes: 5 Folders: 57 - 72
    - History of Residential Rent Control World War II Era (Folder 57, Box 5)
    - Reports and Amendments of NYS Rent Control Laws (Folder 58, Box 5)
    - Study of Rent Control Laws in NYS by Professor Jules -Backman (Folder 59, Box 5)
    - Information on Workman’s Compensation Laws (Folder 60, Box 5)
    - Information on Disability benefits and unemployment insurance (Folder 61, Box 5)
    - Report on Juvenile Delinquency (Folder 62, Box 5)
    - State of NY- Temporary State Commission on Coordination of State Activities (1957) (Folder 63, Box 5)
    - Interim Report of the Joint Legislative Committee to study Illegal Interceptions of Communications (Folder 64, Box 5)
    - Report of NYS joint Legislative Committee to study the problem of Cerebral Palsy (Folder 65, Box 5)
    - Industry-Labor Relations Reports (Folder 66, Box 5)
    - Research on Labor Unions (Folder 67, Box 5)
    - Senate and Assembly Committees on Labor and Industry -Hearing Hughes-Ashbery Bill. February 26, 1957 (Folder 68, Box 5)
    - Information concerning NYS Labor Law (Folder 69, Box 5)
    - Memorandum opposing certain bills sponsored by Temporary State Commission on Coordination of State Activities. February 28, 1957 (Folder 70, Box 5)
    - Summary of Final Report of the Temporary State Commission on Educational Finances (Folder 71, Box 5)
    - Misc. (Folder 72, Box 5)
- 3. Artifacts, 3; 0.5 linear feet Box: 6 Folders: 73 - 74
  Series contains a hand weight from the late nineteenth century and a notary press from the Hackett-Williams law firm also from the late nineteenth century is included.
  By type
  - Hand Weight (Folder 73, Box 6)
  - Notary Press Used in Original Law Offices of Hackett and Williams (Late 1800’s) (Folder 74, Box 6)